Matthew Alunni

https://matthewalunni.github.io/portfolio/ https://github.com/matthewalunni/

Summary

IT professional and Engineering Design student with 5+ years' experience developing web, mobile, and desktop solutions for diverse industry clients. Highly instrumental in all phases of the SDLC, with expertise in data structures and algorithms. Successful in optimizing and automating business procedures.

EDUCATION

Master of Engineering Design in Product Design; GPA: 4.00

McMaster University

Email: matthew.alunni@gmail.com

Mobile: +1-289-442-4004

Coursework: Industrial Automation, IoT, RapidPrototyping, Advanced Robotics and Automation

Bachelor of Computing and Business

Brock University

Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Databases, AI, OOP, Software Engineering, Networking

EXPERIENCE

RBC Toronto, ON

Software Developer II May 2020 - Sept. 2021

- Ticketing Kanban: Worked in an agile environment creating Python/Django web applications using a SQL Server database on the backend to create a ticketing system to manage the work of cybersecurity consultants.
- **Automation**: Worked with and designed RESTful APIs to automate business processes saving thousands of hours for the cybersecurity consulting team.
- **Dashboards**: Used React with Bootstrap and Axios to follow mockups in creating a front-end for a ticketing system, showing graphs, statistics, and graphics.

RBC Toronto, ON

Software Developer

Jan. 2014 - Oct. 2016

- Automation: Independently created C# desktop applications to automate project intake by using analytical skills to save time for members of the cybersecurity department
- Employee Management System: Added utility by creating a .NET application that integrated with tools such as ActiveDirectory to provide convenience for RBC employees.
- SAP Integration: Created Windows forms applications for customers integrating Microsoft Excel to SAP Business One to help customers reduce costs.

Campari Canada

Toronto, ON

Software Developer

July 2018 to Dec. 2018

- Intranet Site: Independently built Campari Canada's intranet site by using Django with a PostGres database, deployed with Heroku to allow Campari to properly organize their internal resources.
- Dashboards: Created responsive dashboards using React to allow for a more fluid experience, integrating internal and external Campari employee resources.
- Data Collection and Storage: Integrated a Python backend with a PostGres database to help efficiently store, edit, and monitor employee data.

PROJECTS

- TowerGrow: A 3D printed IoT desktop hydroponic garden controlled through a react native mobile application
- MFit A Mental Fitness Tracker: A React Native application built for the Niagara Catholic District School Board for students to track and manage their mental health.
- Apple-Music-to-Spotify: This is a script that intakes the url of an Apple Music playlist and uses the Spotify API to create the playlist on Spotify.

Programming Skills

• HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MDBootstrap, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Python, Django, C, .NET, React Native, Java, Git, SQL Server, PostGres, SQLite, Linux, Heroku, Docker, CAD, Cura, Fusion360